So if you look at that, China, first row,
China, 67 percent. That's tariffs charged to the USA, including currency
manipulation and trade barriers. So 67 percent. I think you can, for the most
part, see it. Those with good eyes, with bad eyes. We didn't want to bring — it's
very windy out here — we didn't want to bring out the big charts because it had
no chance of standing. Fortunately, we came armed with a little smaller chart.
So 67 percent. So we're going to be charging a discounted reciprocal tariff
of 34 percent. I think, in other words, they charge us, we charge them, we charge
them less. So how can anybody be upset? They will be, because we never charge
anybody anything. But now we're going to charge. European Union, they're very tough,
very, very tough traders. You know, you think of
China, they're very tough. They're very tough. They're very tough. They're very tough.
European Union, very friendly. They rip us off. It's so sad to see. It's so
pathetic. 39 percent. We're going to charge them 20 percent. So we're charging
them essentially half. Vietnam, great negotiators, great people. They like me. I
like them. The problem is they charge us 90 percent. We're going to charge them 46
percent tariff. Taiwan, where they make — they took all of our computer chips and
semiconductors. We used to be the king, right? We were —
we were everything. We had all of it. Now we have almost none of it, except the biggest
company is coming in. They're going to have — we're going to end up with almost 40 percent.
Lee Zeldin is working to get their approvals. And it's an amazing company. Mr. Wei of
one of the great companies of the world, actually. They're coming in from Taiwan, and they're
going to build one of the biggest plants in the world, maybe the biggest for that. But
64 percent, we're going to charge them 32 percent. Japan, very, very tough. Great people.
And, again, I don't blame the people for doing it. It's — I think they're very smart
at doing it. I blame the people that sat right in that Oval Office right over there, right
behind the Resolute desk or whichever desk they chose. Japan, 46 percent. They would
charge us 46 percent, and much higher for certain items, like cars — you know, little
items like cars. 46 percent, we're charging them 24 percent. India, very, very tough.
Very, very tough. The Prime Minister just left.
And he's a great friend of mine. But I said, you're a friend of mine, but you're not treating
us right. They charged us 52 percent. You have to understand, we charge them almost
nothing for years and years and decades. And it was only seven years ago, when I came in,
we started with China and charged them — we took in hundreds of billions of dollars from
China in tariffs. And they understood, honestly. President Xi understood. He said, look, I
understand. And the other countries — and they all understand.
We're going to have to go through a little tough love, maybe. But they all understand.
They're ripping us off, and they understood it.
Prime Minister of Japan, Shinzo, was Shinzo Abe. He was a fantastic man. He was unfortunately
taken from us — assassination. But I went to him and I said, Shinzo, we have to do something.
A trade is not fair. And he said, I know that. I know that. And he was a great gentleman.
He was a fantastic man. But he understood immediately what I was talking about. I said,
Shinzo, we have to do something. He said, I know that. And we worked out a deal. And
it would have been a much better deal. But, frankly, there were many years left in the
deal that was made previous to my getting there. But it was — it was something.
If you look at Switzerland, 61 percent to 31 percent. Indonesia, Malaysia, Cambodia
— oh, look at Cambodia, 97 percent.
We're going to bring it down.
The Press, too.
The President, too.
President Trump, they're going to bring it down to 40 percent. And they made a fortune
with the United States of America.
United Kingdom, 10 percent! And we'll go 10 percent. So we'll do the same thing.
South Africa, oh, 60 percent, 30 percent. And they've got some bad things going on in
South Africa.
You know, we're paying them billions of dollars. We cut the funding because a lot of bad things
are happening in South Africa. The fake news ought to be looking at it. They don't want
to report it.
Brazil, 10 percent, 10 percent.
The President of the United States,
President Trump, and the United States.
They are very, very tough.
Very, very tough.
The Prime Minister just left, and he's a great
friend of mine, but I said, you're a friend of mine,
but you're not treating us right.
They charged us 52 percent.
You have to understand, we charge them almost
nothing, for years and years and decades.
And it was only seven years ago when I came in,
we started with China in charge, and we took in
hundreds of billions of dollars from China in
tariffs, and they understood, honestly.
President Xi understood.
He said, look, I understand.
And the other countries, and they all understand.
We're going to have to go through a little tough
love, maybe, but they all understand.
They're ripping us off, and they understood it.
Prime Minister of Japan, Shinzo, was Shinzo Abe.
He was a fantastic man.
He was, unfortunately, taken from us.
Assassination.
But I went to him and I said, Shinzo,
we have to do something.
A trade is not fair.
And he said, I know that.
I know that.
And he was a great gentleman.
He was a fantastic man.
But he understood immediately what I was
talking about.
I said, Shinzo, we have to do something.
He said, I know that.
And we worked out a deal.
And it would have been a much better deal, but,
frankly, there were many years left in the deal
that was made previous to my getting there.
But it was something.
If you look at Switzerland, 61 percent
to 31 percent.
Indonesia, Malaysia, Cambodia.
Oh, look at Cambodia, 97 percent.
We're going to bring it down to 49.
They made a fortune with the United States of America.
United Kingdom, 10 percent.
And we'll go 10 percent.
So we'll do the same thing.
South Africa, oh, 60 percent, 30 percent.
And they've got some bad things going on in South Africa.
You know, we're paying them billions of dollars,
and we cut the funding because a lot of bad things.
The President, the United States slashed our trade
barriers on other countries, while those nations placed
massive tariffs on our products and created
outrageous non-monetary barriers to decimate our
industries.
And in many cases, the non-monetary barriers were
worse than the monetary ones.
They manipulated their currencies, subsidized
their exports, stole our intellectual property,
imposed exorbitant VAT taxes to disadvantage our
products.
Adopted unfair rules and technical standards, and
created filthy pollution havens.
They were absolutely filthy, but they always
came to us and they said, we're violating.
We should pay for it.
It's all detailed in a very big report by the U.S.
Trade Representative on Foreign Trade Barriers.
And I'll just hold it up for you.
It's available, and you don't have to pay too much.
As I understand it, you'll pay nothing.
It's a lot of work, a lot of work for something.
Actually, because it's a special book.
It's very, frankly, it's very upsetting when you
read it, when you see what people have been doing to
us for 30 years.
This all happened with no response from the United
States of America, none whatsoever.
But those days are over.
Let me offer just a few examples of the vicious
attacks our workers have faced for so many years.
The United States charges other countries only a
2.4 billion dollars.
That's a lot of money.
And the United States charges a 2.4 billion
dollars more tariff on motorcycles.
Meanwhile, Thailand and others are charging much
higher prices, like 60 percent.
India charges 70 percent.
Vietnam charges 75 percent.
And others are even higher than that.
Likewise, until today, the United States has, for
decades, charged a 2.5 tariff.
Think of that, 2.5 percent on foreign-made
automobiles.
The European Union charges us more than the
United States does.
So, in the United States, they charge an even
10 percent tariff and they have 20 percent VATS.
Much, much higher.
India charges 70 percent, or perhaps worst of all
are the nonmonetary restrictions imposed by
South Korea, Japan, and very many other nations,
as a result of these colossal trade barriers.
Eighty-one percent of the cars in South Korea are
made in South Korea.
Ninety-four percent of the cars in Japan are made in
Japan.
Toyota sells 1.1 billion dollars.
1 million foreign-made automobiles into the
United States, and General Motors sells almost none.
Ford sells very little.
None of our companies are allowed to go into other
countries.
And I say that friend and foe, and in many cases,
the friend is worse than the foe in terms of trade.
But such horrendous imbalances have
devastated our industrial base and put our national
security at risk.
I don't blame these other countries at all for this
calamity.
I blame former presidents and past leaders who
weren't doing their job.
They let it happen, and they let it happen to an
extent that nobody can even believe.
That's why, effective at midnight, we will impose a
25 percent tariff on all foreign-made automobiles.
Thank you.
Brian, I'd like to have you come up here for a second.
Okay?
I just see him sitting.
He's been a fan of ours.
Thank you.
And he understands this business a lot better than
the economists, a lot better than anybody.
Brian, say a few words, please, would you?
Thank you, Mr. President.
It's a great honor to have you.
Thanks.
Thank you, Mr. President.
I grew up just north of Detroit, Michigan, in
Macomb County, known as the home of the Reagan Democrats.
My first vote for President Obama was in